$\texttt{BERKELEY} \cdot \texttt{DAVIS} \cdot \texttt{IRVINE} \cdot \texttt{LOS} \; \texttt{ANGELES} \cdot \texttt{RIVERSIDE} \cdot \texttt{SAN} \; \texttt{DIEGO} \cdot \texttt{SAN} \; \texttt{FRANCISCO}$

SANTA BARBARA · SANTA CRUZ

DEPARTMENT OF MATHEMATICS

RIVERSIDE, CALIFORNIA 92521-0135

baez@math.ucr.edu January 30, 2019

To Whom It May Concern:

.Joshua Meyers entered the math Ph.D. program last fall. He is very intelligent, and he is energetic when he puts his mind to something, but he is flighty and undisciplined. So, it's likely that he would show up for some of course meetings but not all. I am not going to take him on as a student, but this is mainly for a different reason: I have too many students already.

Sincerely,

John C. Baez

Background:

I've read most of Lawvere's Conceptual Mathematics and about half of Riehl's Category Theory in Context. I've participated in the meetings of John Baez's research group at UCR Winter 2019 and plan to continue doing so in Spring 2019.

My father is a linguist, so I learned a lot of linguistics growing up. I also had a philosophy professor as a mentor and close friend during high school and college, so I learned a lot of philosophy.

Ph.D information:

I am not yet in the dissertation-writing phase of my Ph.D. I am in my first year. I don't know yet what the subject matter of my dissertation will be or how long it will take.

Joshua Meyers Curriculum Vitae

Contact	(347)-200-4001	Stony Brook University
Information	joshua.meyers@stonybrook.edu	Department of Mathematics
		Stony Brook, NY 11790

EDUCATION

- · University of California Riverside: Mathematics PhD candidate. 2018-
- · Stony Brook University: Mathematics and Chemistry major. 2014-2018
- · High School for Math, Science and Engineering: 2010-2014

AWARDS

- · 2017 Kuga-Sah Memorial Award Junior Honorary Mention, for outstanding performance in mathematics. Stony Brook University.
- · 2016 Kuga-Sah Memorial Award Sophomore Award, for outstanding performance in mathematics. Stony Brook University.
- · 2013 Gold Medal, level 4 NYC Metropolitan Math Fair
- · 2012 Bronze Award American Association of Teachers of German (AATG)
- · 2011 Finalist, Morton Gould Young Composer Award American Society of Composers, Authors & Publishers (ASCAP)
- · 2011 1st Place, Egg Drop Competition High School for Math, Science, and Engineering

EXPERIENCE

- · 2018-2019 TA at UCR: 20 hours per week of teaching discussion sections, holding office hours, and grading.
- · 2017 Stony Brook Summer Workshop for Students on Topology and Geometry: With Moira Chas, Dennis Sullivan, and Anthony Phillips
- · 2015-2017 Stony Brook Math Club President
- · 2016 Chemistry Research Internship: Goroff group at Stony Brook University. Synthesis of asymmetric polydiacetylenes through cocrystallization and topochemical polymerization, with Professor Nancy Goroff.
- 2014-2015 Online Tutor at InstaEDU
- · 2012-2013 Chemical Engineering Research Internship: PREM (Partnership for Research and Education in Materials) at CCNY. Studied bijels (bicontinuous interfacially jammed emulsion cells), a new class of soft materials, with Professor Raymond Tu.
- 2012-2013 Homework Help. Church of St. Paul and St. Andrew: Tutored elementary school students in all subjects for one hour every week.
- · 2010-present Peer Tutor: Over 400 hours of tutoring fellow students in high school, college, and elsewhere

- Current Projects · Category Theory: teaching myself category theory.
 - · Quantum Mechanics: teaching myself quantum mechanics.
 - Earth Science: teaching myself earth science.
 - · 4D Visualization: working out new techniques and algorithms for visualizing 4 dimensions, involving mathematicians and computer scientists of various levels.
 - Euclid in Greek: reading Euclid's Elements in the original ancient Greek.
 - · School Simulation: making a game that simulates the time management aspects of school.